Guide to the Morris Tyler Family Collection Of John James Audubon
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1826-74; Series IV; 0.8; (2 boxes)
  - WRITINGS OF JOHN JAMES AUDUBON
    - Viviparous Quadrupeds of North America
      - Copyright receipt, vol. 3, partly printed, 1853 (Box 8, Folder 454)
      - Introduction, holograph, 1844 Dec 23 (Box 8, Folder 455)
        The chapters that follow are holograph manuscripts, most in the hand of Victor Audubon
      - "Arctomys Flaviventer", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 456)
      - "Armadillo" [fragment], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 457)
      - "Arvicola Borealis", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 458)
      - "Arvicola Drummondii" (Box 8, Folder 459)
      - "Arvicola Texiana", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 460)
      - "Bassaris Astuta...Ringtail bassaris", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 461)
      - "Buffalo", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 462)
      - "Canis familiaris...Hare Indian dog" [fragment] (Box 8, Folder 463)
      - "Canis latrans...Prairie Wolf", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 464)
      - "Canis lupus...Black American Wolf", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 465)
      - "Canis lupus...White American wolf", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 466)
      - "Canis (vulpes) fulvus...American Cross Fox", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 467)
      - "Cervus alces...Moose deer", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 468)
      - "Cervus leucurus...Longtailed deer", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 469)
      - "Cervus macrotis...Mule deer", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 470)
      - "Cervus Richardsonii...Columbian Black-tailed deer", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 471)
      - "Col. McCall's account of the Texan Skunk", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 472)
      - "Condylura Cristata...Common Star- nose mole" (Box 8, Folder 473)
      - "Dipodomys Phillippsii...Pouched jerboa mouse", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 474)
      - "Elk or Wapite", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 475)
      - "Enhydra Marina...Sea otter", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 476)
      - "Felis Onca...Jaguar", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 477)
        See also: Oversize, Box 15, folder 712
      - "Felis pardalis...Ocelot or Leopard- cat", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 478)
      - "Georychus trimucronatus", n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 713
      - "Horns of the American Rein-deer" (Box 8, Folder 479)
      - "John's account of Sciurus Sub-auratus", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 480)
      - "Lepus Glacialis...Polar Hare", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 481)
      - "Lepus Nigricaudatus...Black-tailed hare", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 482)
      - "Lepus Nuttallii...Nutalli hare", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 483)
      - "Lepus Texianus...Texan Hare", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 484)
      - "Lutra Canadensis...Common American Otter", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 485)
      - [Meles Labradoria...American badger] fragment, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 486)
      - "Mephitis Americana - Common American Skunk", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 487)
      - "Mephitis mesoleuca...Texan Skunk", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 488)
      - "Moose deer", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 489)
      - "Mus Aureolus...Orange-coloured mouse", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 490)
      - "Mus Decumanus...Brown or Norway Rat", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 491)
      - "Mus humilis...Little harvest mouse", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 492)
      - "Mustela Martes...Pine Marten", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 493)
      - "Notes on the American Hare", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 494)
      - "Notes on the Skunk", n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 714
      - "Opossum" [fragment], n.d. (Box 9, Folder 495)
      - "Ovibos Moschatus...Musk Ox", n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 715
      - "Ovis Montana...Rocky Mountain Sheep", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 496)
      - "Procyon [Lotor]...Raccoon" [p. 2 missing], n.d. (Box 9, Folder 497)
      - "Pronghorned antelope", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 498)
      - "Pseudostoma borealis...", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 499)
      - "Pseudostoma Douglasii...Columbian pouched rat", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 500)
      - "Pteromys Oregonensis...Oregon Flying Squirrel", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 501)
      - "Pteromys Volucella - Common flying squirrel", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 502)
      - "Putorius frenata...Bridled weasel", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 503)
      - "Red Texan wolf", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 504)
      - "Scalops Brewerii...Brewer's Shrew Mole", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 505)
      - "Sciurus Carolinensis...Carolina Grey Squirrel", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 506)
      - "Sciurus Collæi" [fragment], n.d. (Box 9, Folder 507)
      - "Sciurus Leporinus...Hare Squirrel", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 508)
      - "Sciurus Migratorius...", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 509)
      - "Sciurus Mollipilosus...Soft-haired Squirrel", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 510)
      - "Sciurus Richardsonii...Richardson's Columbian Squirrel", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 511)
      - "Sciurus Rubricaudatus...", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 512)
      - "Sciurus Sub-auratus...Golden bellied squirrel", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 513)
      - "Sorex Carolinensis...Carolina shrew", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 514)
      - "Sorex DeKayi", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 515)
      - "Sorex parvus...Say's least Shrew", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 516)
      - "Spermophilus tridecem lineatus... Leopard Spermophile", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 517)
      - "[Ursus Americanus...American] Black bear", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 518)
      - "Ursus ferox...Grizzly bear", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 519)
      - "Vulpes Velox...Swift Fox", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 520)
      - "Weasel", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 521)
      - "The White Bear", 1846 Aug 1 (Box 9, Folder 522)
    - "The White Perch and its favorite Bait," holograph
      See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 716
      Part of Ornithological Biography, "Delineations of American Scenery and Manners"
    - Unidentified fragments, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 523)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Adam, Reverend Mr.
      - "Extract concerning Mr Audubon from a lecture...," manuscript, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 524)
    - Audubon, Annie
      - Untitled essay on Audubon, holograph, 1872-74 (Box 9, Folder 525)
    - Audubon, Eliza
      - "My William, I'll soon be with you," manuscript, fragment, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 526)
    - Audubon, Victor Gifford
      - Untitled, holograph: "It was a beautiful morning, the 16 Oct[obe]r, of the year 1832, that I stood on the deck of the small steamer 'Rufus King' ... ", n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 717
    - Bachman, John
      - "An account of some experiments made on the habits of the Vultures...", printed version, 1834 Jan 18 (Box 9, Folder 527)
      - "The Bats," holograph (Box 9, Folder 528)
        - With: ALS to ? from John Bachman, n.d.
      - "Monograph of the Genus Scirus with Descriptions of new Species and their Varieties, as existing in North America," printed version, 1839 (Box 9, Folder 529)
    - Baird, Spencer F.
      - "About Birds," holograph, 1842 Jan 14 (Box 9, Folder 530)
    - Elliot, Ebenezer
      - "Lines written by the author of Cornlaw Rhymes on seeing at the residence of Mr. Heppenstall of Upper Thorpe near Sheffield, the plates of Audubon's Birds of America," holograph, 1835 Sep (Box 9, Folder 531)
    - Harris, Edward
      - Untitled, letter to the Committee of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia on the geology of the Upper Missouri, printed version, with annotations, 1845 (Box 9, Folder 532)
    - McCall, George A.
      - "Some Remarks on the Habits &c., of Birds met with in Western Texas, between San Antonio and the Rio Grande and in New Mexico," printed version, 1851 (Box 9, Folder 533)
    - McCulloch, T. [Thomas], Jr.
      - "Shrix Noctua," holograph, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 534)
    - Sharpless, John T.
      - "Wild Swan. Cygnus Ferus," printed version, with annotations, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 718
    - Unidentified authors
      - "Ho! for California," manuscript, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 535)
      - "Chesapeake Duck Shooting.," printed, clipping, annotated, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 536)
      - Untitled, observations on Kentucky 1800-20, manuscript, fragment, with fragment addressed to Richard Harlan, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 537)
- Audubon Family Papers, 1806-77; Series V; 0.2; (1 box)
  Series V, Audubon Family Papers, is organized in three subseries: Financial and Legal Papers; Maps and Floor Plans; and Other Papers. Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material.
  - FINANCIAL AND LEGAL PAPERS
    - Authorization for payment to Robert Lanier, in JJA's hand, 1830 (Box 10, Folder 538)
    - Bank note, signed over to JJA by William H. Lizars, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 539)
    - Bill from Trinity Church, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 540)
    - Bill from Adam and Charles Black for books purchased by JJA, 1835 (Box 10, Folder 541)
    - Bill of exchange, signed by JJA and J. Berthoud & Son, 1820 (Box 10, Folder 542)
    - Charter securing a vessel for JJA's Labrador trip, 1833 Jun 5
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 719
    - Contract [photocopy], 1806
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 720
    - Deeds for land, Henderson, Kentucky, 1816 Dec 31 (Box 10, Folder 543)
    - Draft of an agreement regarding settlement of Jean Audubon's estate, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 544)
    - Insurance policy providing coverage for Birds of America drawings shipped to London, 1834 Jan 18
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 721
    - Receipt by Robert Havell, 1829 Mar 30
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 722
    - Receipts, 1832-55 (Box 10, Folder 545)
  - MAPS AND PLANS
    - Entrance to Apalachicola Bay, drawn by N. L. Coste, 1834
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 723
    - House plans, drawn by JWA, 1851
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 724
    - "Map of country seat at Fort Washington," printed, 1855
      See: Oversize, Box 17, folder 744
    - Minnie's Land
      - "Executors Sale of Valuable Real Estate & Water Rights... Estate of J. J. Audubon. Dec[ease]d to be sold at auction by Cole & Clinton, Auct[ionee]rs on Monday 13th Oct[obe]r 1851...," printed, with annotations
        See: Oversize, Box 17, folder 745
      - "Location of Audubon property," in ink, colored, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 546)
      - "Map of March 1872 surveyed by Mess. Michaels & Melendy", 1872 Mar
        See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 725
      - "Plan of Minnies Land the Property of the Late John James Audubon Esq.", 1874 Jun 12
        See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 726
      - Untitled, showing 155th - 158th Street, in ink, signed "F. T. Vidal, City Surveyor", n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 727
    - Mouth of Mannatee River, drawn by N. L. Coste, 1834
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 728
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Academy of Natural Sciences: resolution in honor of Audubon, manuscript, 1851 Feb 4 (Box 10, Folder 547)
    - American Philosophical Society: membership notice, partly printed, 1831 Jul 15 (Box 10, Folder 548)
    - Audubon, Victor Gifford: passport, 1836
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 729
    - Exhibition admission tickets, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 549)
      Incl: admission pass in Audubon's hand for Daniel Mallory and family
    - Havell, Robert: sale catalog of paintings, clipping, 1877, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 550)
    - Natural History Society: membership certificate, partly printed, 1830 Nov 15 (Box 10, Folder 551)
    - Permission to pass through Indian country granted to Audubon, partly printed, 1843 Apr 19 (Box 10, Folder 552)
    - Robertson, John: passport, 1828
      - Annotated in JJA's hand "Papers given me as a Curiousity by John Robertson Esq. 1828"
        See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 730
    - Royal Society
      - Election list, printed, with annotations, 1830
        See: Oversize, Box 17, folder 746
      - Meeting admission ticket for JJA, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 553)
    - Sachet, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 554)
    - Société entomologique de France: list of members, printed, 1832 (Box 10, Folder 555)
- Tyler Research Files, 1927-1980; Series VI; 0.6; (2 boxes)
  Series VI, Tyler Research Files, is organized by type of material. The transcripts of correspondence (of letters from the collection and of others for which the location of the original is not known) are arranged alphabetically by letter writer and then chronologically.
  - Booklets and pamphlets on Audubon
    - Grinnell, George Bird: Audubon Park: The History of the Site of the Hispanic Society of America and Neighbouring Institutions, New York: printed by order of the trustees, printed monograph, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 556)
    - Martin, Eda W.: Audubon in Richmond, Richmond, Virginia: The Valentine Museum, printed monograph, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 557)
    - Murphy, Robert Cushman: "John James Audubon (1785-1851): An Evaluation of the Man and His Work," reprinted from The New-York Historical Society Quarterly, 1956 Oct (Box 11, Folder 558)
    - The Print Collector, No. Six, "Special Audubon Issue," catalog of Kenneth Nebenzahl, Inc., 1970 (Box 11, Folder 559)
    - Specialized Collection of Territorial & Early Indiana Covers and Specialized Collection of Presidential Letters, catalog for auction by John A. Fox, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 560)
    - Van Nostrand, Jeanne Skinner: "Audubon's Ill-Fated Western Journey," offprint from California Historical Society Quarterly, 1943 Dec (Box 11, Folder 561)
  - Clippings, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 562)
  - Correspondence, 1931-71, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 563)
  - Photographs
    - Of paintings by or of Audubon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 564)
    - Of unidentified people and places (Box 11, Folder 565-566)
  - Research notes, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 567-573)
  - Research notes, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 574-575)
  - Transcripts
    - Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 576-580)
      Of letters by JJA, LBA, VGA, and others. Transcripts are undated; originals were dated from 1802 to 1856
      See also: Oversize, Box 16, folder 731
    - [Dictaphone?] recording of oral transcriptions of Audubon correspondence (Box 12, Folder 581)
    - Interviews with Harriet Audubon and Alicia Shaffer, 1931-34, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 582)
    - Power of attorney granted to Jean Audubon for several investors, French transcript and translation, original dated 1790 Apr (Box 12, Folder 583)
- Autograph Collection, 1697-1887; Series VII; 0.6; (2 boxes)
  Series VII, Autograph Collection is organized in five subseries: Correspondence; Scrapbook; Writings; Other Documents; and Prints. Materials are arranged alphabetically by letter writer, author, signer of the document, or engraver or artist. A long descriptive note for the Scrapbook, found in the Oversize section of the register, provides name access to the material it contains and is given in series order with scrapbook page numbers provided.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Adams, C. F. to ?, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 584)
    - Alexander, James Waddel to D. Potter
    - Alexander, Stephen to ---- Fisk, 1859 Mar 31
    - Anderson, Joseph to Hugh McCall, 1819 Nov 2 (Box 13, Folder 585)
    - Anderson, Joseph to Wade, Major W., 1830 Jan 13
    - Armstrong, James to Andrew H. Foote, 1857 Dec 2
    - Bell, John Gray to ?, 1857 Oct 15 (Box 13, Folder 586)
    - Bishop, Henry[?] to I.[?] Winston, 1825 Dec 5
    - Bishop, W. D. to I. T. Rogers[?], 1866 Mar 17
    - Bissell, Clark to S. J. Hitchcock, 1828 Nov 17 (Box 13, Folder 587)
    - Boughton, G. H. to T. A. Richards, 1857 Jan 19
    - Bradford[?], I.[?] H. to E. G. Knight, 1867 Mar 29 (Box 13, Folder 588)
    - Bradley, James P. to ?, 1872 Apr 19
    - Breckinridge, J. D. to Charles S. Todd, 1818 Apr 1
    - Brent, Daniel to Henry Clay, Jr., 1836 Feb 24 (Box 13, Folder 589)
    - Brooks, Phillips to Donald ----, 1881 Mar 31
    - Browne, Charles F.
      See: Artemus Ward
    - Buchanan, James, 1861 Aug 8 (Box 13, Folder 590)
    - Burke, Edmund, 1841 Apr 6 (Box 13, Folder 591)
    - Canning, Stratford to W. D. Williamson, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 592)
    - Carey, Henry Charles to ---- Howland[?], 1868 Apr 20
    - Carey, Mathew to Howe & Deforest[?], 1813 Jan 18
    - Carey, Mathew to Daniel Steele, 1815 May 28
    - Chambers, John to James Morrison, 1821 Sep 28 (Box 13, Folder 593)
    - Childs, ---- to P. Cleaveland, 1827 Sep 20
    - Chivres, Thomas H. to E. H. Leffingwell, 1853 Sep 4 (Box 13, Folder 594)
    - Claxton, T. to Joseph M. Wightman, 1843 Nov 3
    - Clay, Henry to Daniel Mallory, 1826, 1827 (Box 13, Folder 595)
      With: note from James Barbour, Secretary of War, 1826 Dec 4
    - Clay, Henry to Daniel Mallory, 1830-39 (Box 13, Folder 596)
    - Clay, Henry to Daniel Mallory, 1842-43 (Box 13, Folder 597)
    - Clay, Henry [fragment], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 598)
    - Cleaveland, P. to Mary A. Cleaveland Conkling, Roscoe to Mr. Boutwell, 1876 Mar 18 (Box 13, Folder 599)
    - Cooper, Thomas[?] to Thomas Brownell[?], 1845 Dec 31
    - Coxe, Tench to James M. Lingan, 1791 (Box 13, Folder 600)
    - Cuyler, Theo. L. to Peter ----, 1872 Jan 21
    - Dallas, Alexander James to ?, 1815 Aug 18 (Box 13, Folder 601)
    - Day, Thomas to John T. Gilman, 1814 Oct 4
    - De Koven, James to ?, 1861 Apr 24
    - Dix, Dorothy L., n.d. (Box 13, Folder 602)
    - Doane, George Washington to T. Abbott, 1843 Apr 28 (Box 13, Folder 603)
    - Dobbin, James C. to A. H. Foote, 1855 Feb 2
    - Dougherty, Thomas to ?, 1820 Oct 26
    - Emerson, Ralph Waldo to Miss Prescott, 1862 Mar 15 (Box 13, Folder 604)
    - Fenton, R., 1865 Mar 1 (Box 13, Folder 605)
    - Fields, James T. to Miss Prescott, 1862 Mar 15
    - Fields, J. T. to ?, 1877 Nov. 24
    - Fillmore, Millard to Henry R. Howland, 1871 (Box 13, Folder 606)
    - Fillmore, Millard [fragment], 1861 Apr 4
    - Fitzpatrick, Benjamin to T. M. Tucker, 1842 Mar 18 (Box 13, Folder 607)
    - Gavin[?], W.[?] M. to Col. Kincannon, 1843 Feb 13 (Box 13, Folder 608)
    - Giles[?], Henry to ?, 1848 Oct 21
    - Gilman, D. C. to Frank Tyler, 1836 Jun 3
    - Goodrich, Samuel G. to George Savage, 1857 Nov 25 (Box 13, Folder 609)
    - Goodwin, H. E. B. to ?, 1857 Sep 9
    - Gray, Asa to P. Cleveland, 1845 May 23 (Box 13, Folder 610)
    - Gray, William to Abraham Watson, 1798 May 19
    - Greenleaf, Simon to S.[?] C. Munn, 1852 Dec 4
    - Guyot, A. to T. D. Dana, 1857 Feb 12
    - Halsted, William to T.[?] Abbot[?], 1842 Apr 9 (Box 13, Folder 611)
    - Heinrich, Anthony Philip to ?, 1830 Nov 4
    - Hickok, L. P. to William ----, 1811 Aug 5
    - Hooker, J. to ---- Shanks, 1877 Dec 29
    - Howe, Hezekiah from:
      - Armstrong, L. T., 1816 (Box 13, Folder 612)
      - Comstock, J. L., 1833 May 28
      - Dutton, Henry, 1832 Oct 26
      - Grimké, Thomas, 1831 Apr 1
      - Skinner, A. N., n.d. (Box 13, Folder 613)
      - Smith, Truman[?], 1832 Sep 24
      - Tyler, Bennett, 1817 Mar 17
    - Humboldt, Alexander von to W. W. H. Davis [translation in unknown hand], 1858 Aug 12 (Box 13, Folder 614)
    - Hunt, W. H. to John Knowen, 1855 Mar 29
    - Irving, Henry[?] to Inspector Denning, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 615)
    - James Munroe & Co. from:
      - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1839 Nov 9 (Box 13, Folder 616)
      - Farley, Harriet, 1834 Mar 17 (Box 13, Folder 617)
      - Felton, C. C., 1856 Jul 3
      - Frost, John, 1844 Apr 29
      - Gilman, Caroline, 1850 Nov. 5 (Box 13, Folder 618)
      - Gilman, S., 1842 Jan 23
      - Sales, Francis, 1842 Apr 4 (Box 13, Folder 619)
      - Sears, E. J., 1859 Feb 22
      - Seymour, A., 1853 Mar 25
    - Jefferson, Joseph to Daniel Mallory, 1824, 1829 (Box 13, Folder 620)
    - Johnson, William to J. A. Gregory, 1849 Dec 3
    - Lanciani, Rodolfo to ?, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 621)
    - Lanman, Charles to Benjamin Perley Poore, 1849 Jun 29
    - Littell, John Stockton to Van Amringe & Bixby, 1844 Jun 1 (Box 13, Folder 622)
    - Livingston, [William], 1781 Nov 12
    - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth [fragment], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 623)
    - McCulloch, Hugh to W. C. Beardsley, 1868 Oct 13 (Box 13, Folder 624)
    - Maclean, John, 1874 Jul 22
    - Mann, Horace to Robert Carter, 1851 Nov 8
    - Marignac[?] P. to ?, 1872 Jul 23 (Box 13, Folder 625)
    - Maverick, Peter to W. W. Woodward, 1810 Aug 22
    - Meigs, Return Jonathan to William Murphy, 1817 Nov 24 (Box 13, Folder 626)
    - Mullens, ---- to Charles Morse, 1852 Jan 20
    - Noyes, Edward F. to Thomas Foulds, 1869 (Box 13, Folder 627)
    - Palfrey, John G. to William A. Baker, 1866 Mar 26 (Box 13, Folder 628)
    - Pattison, Granville Sharp to Charles Cumber, 1829 Aug 8
    - Paulding, William I. to Henry R. Howland, 1869 Jul 31 (Box 13, Folder 629)
    - Peale, Rembrandt [fragment]
    - Pendleton, George H. to R. M. Corwin[?], 1851 Feb 10 (Box 13, Folder 630)
    - Phelps, William F. to J. Fisk, 1860 Jun 7
    - Phillips, Wendell to Gov. Long, 1882 Jan 18
    - Polhemus, John to James Rice, 1817 Dec 30 (Box 13, Folder 631)
    - Porter, Noah, 1869 Jun (Box 13, Folder 632)
    - Rideing, William H. [fragment], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 633)
    - Risby, H. A. to ?, 1867 Jul 3
    - Scott, Winfield to the officers of the United States Army, 1842 Jul 25 (Box 13, Folder 634)
    - Sedgwick, C. M. to William Ashburner, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 635)
    - Seward, Theodore F. to William B. Bradbury, 1864 Oct 29
    - Seward, William H. to Joseph Leyman, 1837 Aug 22
    - Sherman, Roger Minott to Staples & Hitchcock, 1821 Feb 23 (Box 13, Folder 636)
    - Shonts[?], R. S. to ?, 1882, n.d.
    - Siddons, J. H. to ?, 1875 Aug 21 (Box 13, Folder 637)
    - Simpson, Sir George to John H. Scott, 1845 Nov 21
    - Slade, William to C.K. Williams, 1823 Nov 12 (Box 13, Folder 638)
    - Smith, Aug. W. to ---- Leffingwell, 1854 May 8
    - Smith, John Cotton to Donald ----, 1881 Apr 7
    - Smith, Joseph to A. H. Foote, 1849 Oct 29
    - Smith, English & Co. from:
      - Allen, Rev D. H., 1860 Nov 5 (Box 13, Folder 639)
      - Anderson, T.[?] C., 1860 Oct 20
      - Barrows, P., 1860 Oct 1
      - Bartlell[?], Samuel[?] C., 1861 Jan 31
      - Champlin, James T., 1860 Oct 4 (Box 13, Folder 640)
      - Church, A., 1860 Oct 31
      - Cobleigh, N. E., 1861 Jan 23
      - Fisher, Samuel[?] W., 1861 Jan 15 (Box 13, Folder 641)
      - Geshart, V.[?] V., 1860 Nov. 15
      - Green, Henry, 1868 Dec 18
      - Haven, Joseph, 1860 Oct 24
      - Lawson, George W.[?], 1860 Sep 27 (Box 13, Folder 642)
      - Merrill, John W., 1860 Oct 11
      - Pratt, C.[?] W., 1860 Nov 17
      - Scott, J. W., 1860 Dec 31 (Box 13, Folder 643)
      - Smith, Daniel Talcott, 1860 Dec 10
      - Sparrow, William, 1860 Oct 6
      - Vail, Stephen M., 1860 Oct 15
    - Southard, Samuel to Daniel Mallory, 1831 (Box 13, Folder 644)
    - Sprague, William B. to Dr. Paine, 1872 Apr 14 (Box 13, Folder 645)
    - Stanley, Henry M. to Benjamin Scott, 1887 Jan 3
    - Stedman, Edmund Clarence to ?, 1875 Jan 12
    - Stone, A. L. (Andrew Leete) to Byron C. Smith, 1863 Dec 11 (Box 13, Folder 646)
    - Storrs, William L. to Henry White, 1848 Apr 10
    - Taylor, J. Bayard to Bennett ----, 1857 Oct 13 (Box 13, Folder 647)
    - United States. Consulate (Society Islands) to John Mill, 1841 Mar 10 (Box 13, Folder 648)
    - United States. Treasury Department to Samuel N. Salomon, 1871 Mar 11
    - Van Ness, C. D. to Mr. Young, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 649)
    - Van Rensselaer, C. to J. M. Macdonald, 1859 Oct 4
    - Vincent, Frank to M. Frank Tyler, 1875 May 7
    - Waite, Henry M. to ?, 1827 Oct 25 (Box 13, Folder 650)
    - Ward, Artemus to ?, 1862 Nov 9
    - Watson, Henry C. to B. Bradbury, 1864 Jul 19
    - Webber, C. W. to ?, 1851 Jan 25
    - Webster, Noah to Lavin J. Gist, 1837 Feb 9 (Box 13, Folder 651)
    - Webster, W. G. to ?, 1827 Nov 17
    - Westmoreland, J. to Mrs. Tileston (Box 13, Folder 652)
    - Whiting, George B. to William Leffingwell, 1863 Apr 7
    - Whittingham, William Rollinson to Rev. Shelton, 1840 Sep 14 (Box 13, Folder 653)
    - Wilbur, Henry to Durrie and Peck, 1831 Jul 9
    - Wilde, Oscar [autograph], n.d.
    - Wood, William to ---- Wade, 1879 Dec 12 (Box 13, Folder 654)
    - Woodruff, John to ---- Thomas, 1886 Dec 19
    - Unidentified, 1844-93, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 655)
  - SCRAPBOOK
    See: Oversize, Box 18, folder 748
    - Contents are listed in detail in the Oversize section of the
      register, pages 60-62
  - WRITINGS
    - Bourne, William Oland: "Look to Jesus" (Box 13, Folder 656)